Welcome, welcome to build and welcome
...san-francisco as we settle down let's make sure that
...give enough room for people coming in I was told to in this message because last couple of sessions
...ogg give yourself some room and make...comes and the trickle.
The art
...cartography has evolved over thousands of years we've come a long
Nowadays any app that has a real-world action is expected to be location
aware and display this information richly on a map this is will be
...this is expected what's next what's the next natural
evolution of cartography introducing theory for windows apps.
These are not just images these are actual three-d words that you
could customize and display
your information microsoft has open these three-d words for you.
Hi, my name is robyn...and with me I have might
...we are both program managers working on the map stockholm for windows we are
here probably...maps and location d at microsoft.
Today we will build...app
...display information in three-d and it will take advantage of
the street-side imagery that we have.
To get to that app we will go over the basic features that
the maps platform on windows has to offer and we'll also look
at how your feedback has influenced the product and how your feedback has
includes the platform features that we have introduce in windows?
Before we get into talking about the features in windows and,
the platform I wanted...talk about what does...backed off often
prop work on the end-user...a biggest impact that we had in windows eight-point
one we had seven different apps with seven different features and functionality on
a variety of devices catering to a bunch of different experiences the
user had to choose and pick from these apps.
In windows stand we've combined all these seven different apps and functionalities
to one single powerful
app that works seamlessly across phone tablets and
...and the windows devices.
This is an important thing the one thing that we have to note out
here is this maps app is built on top of the...maps platform
...is available to developers as you might have seen all throughout the day and other previous eml
tocs how we are building on top of the same platform that we're giving to you map
platform...the same thing a default windows maps app uses the same maps platform.
So, what are the different
features and challenges of that we had in the maps platform?
As we know in windows phone fiat you relied heavily on the here location platform
...desktop side of things relied on the bing so, map services.
We don't really want to make this as part of your
...so as maps platform
we've combined all the features and functionalities from the to services and combine them into
one maps platform so you can start using it from one place.
To features include a basic
two-d map that you can display the basic canvas instead of a map control instead of
your map app you can customize the information that you want to display in the map.
...transit traffic information then obviously you want to put your
own push...and...on your own custom data on top of
the map we have that feature for you then you want to
display you want to be location wave and you want you want to define regions so
that when the user enters a certain region or when...use...region you
get events we have those api and features for-you?
Node that code...on windows devices uses the
same geo fencing services that are offered...in the map platform.
Then we have some advanced features and functionalities like routing we provide you
...from point a to point b we can provide you driving route and
...can for-you walking round we can make the...to the...demise...
for your restrictions let's say you want to...you want all-white highways you can do that.
You can also you can also get our routers optimize
four-time versus distance and optimized for graphic so on these are features that...already part of
windows phone eight but along the way we have taken feedback and we've improved them and
...made improve part of the windows...maps platform.
Now we're getting into some of the new and exciting stuff.
For the first-time in this release we are introducing offline map support for desktops and
tablet.
This means that we have a system-wide
offline map setting once the user downloads a map offline
on the device is available for all of the apps on the device.
Develop a variety of scenarios that coming to mind when it comes to offline maps...so you have a
backed backpacking trip to europe and you want to...and,
maintain a travel journal you can do that using offline maps you carry your offline not but
you've got your surface...with you and you can you can blog about it but you cannot be uploaded to
the into an obviously but you could...so you can later
...travel journal the bunch of scenarios that come to mind when it comes offline maps.
Next...provide and give you the rich
street-side capabilities this is the first-time interesting street-side capabilities on phone that
...you have you can now go on and
...street-side which is the view of the street
...a given lat long at the given camera angle you can customize it and you can displayed as part of
your app then obviously we're going to give you the three-d that I open web we have the three-d capabilities
of which is on...tablets and bcs
...big so think about the scenarios are capable out
here imagine now that I trouble too close you key
...and I troubled my wife and I...the sophie of me mobile with the building
ascended to mammal she has a windows device you open the picture and,...
this is a picture of me traveling but imagine absence scenarios where
now you can have instant panorama of these three-d buildings that I can send to my mom
along with the picture she can really relate to where I am and what I have
traveled this amazing so we'll see how you can customize and use...sort of things
...obviously these features...built on top of the windows universal
...universal windows platform which means these are adaptive
across different device screens and device sizes and resolutions these
adapt to different input types like mouse keyboard and touch?
And, this one binding that you can run and apply we'll see how we...today.
So, this is good these are all the features you have what are the api...that...we can take a look at.
So, you have different map location services
rate so you need to have two different service authentication
...you need to have two different service tokens so will point you...different websites
for it no we have done all the hard work to make sure
...unify all the authentication framework into one
place...all you have to do is you go to one place bing naps portal
selected drop down universal windows platform and you get a service token that
...use in your app and...just this in your
...in your app before you put it on the store.
We have this is this slide is basically going to cover the things that you can search
on look for get started on we had the name space windows you
...controls maps this where you'll find all the view or the
widely that things when it comes to the map control includes the basic map control that you...
sample includes map elements these are things that you can embed instead of
your map control map elements can be of three different types map
icons map poly lines and map polygons these are things you can
embed inside of your map...then we have this good old sample
that you can put on top of the map and you can assign it a location and...the
...displayed on your map you can also completely
...on the map control using the map by sources or you can overlay
or own tiles on top of the map control this is very common in
whether scenarios and, a lot of people have been using it as a very common scenario for map
bias makes you want location so we have a windows devices start geo location
...this is where you get the location and
you fencing services there's a talk earlier talking about background
task how you can access geo location in the background I think it was by...so check it out if you
...figure out onlineyou'll get more information how to access...the background.
Then we have other head less routing services or other
...map services that you can include
...can use this includes the location finder this is for geo coding and
...geo coding.
We have mapped out finder service this is
...gives you route from pointy to...to see to ds one.
Then this part is my favorite we have.
The uri scheme I say this my...because with
...of code you launched existing maps abbott's a default maps app you
possum the parameters you want and...complete your...scenario, for example,
let's say you...directions you want to give user directions you
are restaurant app and you don't really care about getting directions included in your...you want to do is
...to give the user the direction for that you just compose your uri scheme and
you build it and then you launch the uri and now you...in the maps app and user gets what they want.
Let's go over the basics of map control.
You refer the name space.
The windows us downloading space example file you add that
...of code and you have the map controlled displayed for you.
Then you want to customize and put it on a center so you put the map duped
your sinus center for your map control in this case it san-francisco assigned a zoom level
to itand, it will displayed correctly on the mackerel that's the simple code.
And, you want to display your.
...display your own information on top of the map
control...that we have the map icon type that we talked about earlier you
instantiate the map icon you assign the right properties to it properties...you give it an image
...this image will be displayed on the map control.
Then you then you want to give it the collision
behavior desired property this is the property which...based on
...feedback and the this is how you have influence our product so it used to be that when you zoom
out we would hide the map icons when you zoom out and,
this was this was good for the map but...not really they can
role by the developers so we heard that and, we added this property so now when you include
...many make it remains visible the map icon is always...the zoom level.
Then we have the...anchor property off-course you assign location to the map
icon use bitmap icon you put a location on the map icon then we had the
normalize anchor point so when you put an image on top of the
map where does the image get attached to that location for that we have normalizing
...so as you can see in this particular case I want the image to attach
the location ad zero-point-five...a one and this is how you do a
normalize ical point you use the normalizing...point to customize how you want to display the map ical.
The new once a map icon is created you assign the map
that you add the map icon to the map elements collection remember this to do three different
types of map elements are map icon map...line and map polygon map
...is just one type and similarly you can do poly lines and polygons.
Next we...you want to...space example on top of the map control in this case I have
a user control I'm creating user control and I'm putting it attaching
it to location but first...to the children collection and then
advertising to location and this will display the basic example forming.
Then the uri scheme this is the
...schemas talking earlier of how you can easily build a uri scheme
...the right parameters and what
parameters are available to you is in a very nice document and available in the resource
...towards the end and this one-line of core will give will launch the windows maps
app and it will give user direction from mountain you to
san francisco and this is direction is something that I keep repeating on but
you'd be surprised at how many different parameters and capabilities are available in the
ui scheme format so we'll check it out it's pretty awesome next you
want uses location for that we have the geo locate
or service and using the geo location
...you get geo location asic call you can get the users your location?
...location is something that is very private to the user so we
have a couple of security points and place to make sure you center-right.
before you submit your app or before you run your app make sure you have the...
Device capability set-up in your package...manifest file otherwise you get someone
time exceptions...compile-time exceptions.
Then what...want to do is before you axes users location?
...want use this permission if you don't provide the user does not
...permission then you will not get users location to make sure that you have
users location you need to make a call to you located dot request access
basic.
And, once you have...location then once you allow
...location then make a call to the...look at...service.
If...denied...users location then be graceful
show the right dialogues or maybe don't show the dialogues and...for the right time to gain...permission.
This brings us to the consent location consent users location
is a very personal and private thing you have responsibility me as a framework have
a responsibility so we try to do everything that is right...
...thing to note is...provide the system provided prompt so
any timeanytime during runtime whenever you access user location we
will provide a prompt for the user asking user that page you want to give this
after your location and if the user denies and then you don't get
...location it used to be in windows phone that we would do
this check at install time and your apple not installed that's no longer the case.
In windows ten and forward we will do this checked at runtime but
your existing windows phone...app should, should work fine so don't worry about that.
So, we provide system in app brahms for users location this prom shows up the very
first-time you try to access location or the very
first-time you make the request access casing call that
...your control and went to make let's say now the user has denied it
that you access the can any time go back to the privacy setting and
change the decision this is again given the our to the user and, making sure the...has a
...location privacy settings.
These are the things we've done for the user how can you make sure that you are you're doing
your app quickly making the app correctly and we can
write checks again to remind everyone remove your own custom problems we have the system
proms for you make sure that you don't need to have your own toggle switch privacy settings in
your app we have a system-wide unified way to do privacy management for the user
...the request access...call on the...thread.
This important note because before you access the location in the background
thread you need to come to the widespread and act and get
users permission otherwise you will not get location.
And, then finally if you would like at some point you can probably do
a uri launch into the privacy settings for your app and request user
to again reconsider the location decision.
Nowwe'll have to demos today we'll have a basic one-oh-one demo
...show you just point you sampled on...where you can go and we'll
have other app which we saw...in the screenshot that we'll talk about.
...switch.
So, the app that we have today is.
Is very...to san-francisco...notice that there's a lot of movies that are shot
in san francisco there's a bunch of locations...san-francisco it has a
lot of culture and a lot of movies want to take advantage of that so,
what we did was we found a data source which provides says with all the locations
...in san francisco movies were shot and it has a lat long and we're going to
display that richly on a map and will help user figure out...what are the different
informations on that movie about that movie will help them?
Select and pick which locations they want to go and tour.
And, they will...pick they will look at the route where they want to
...and then finally we'll give them directions to a meeting place where they can come and,
...you take the to...will take them so for that would have is a basic json file.
Old yet let's let.
Let's go the basic sample so in the basic sample this is
the sample that we have shipped with a is...out and,
it is on the get hub it is along with other
samples that we have in this casewhat I'm doing is I have three different sliders and data binding it
to different properties on the map control I have a few check boxes which
helped me customize the map and, the sample is very basic the
...is very straightforward and simple for you to go play with...a bunch of different scenarios and,
this in the sample that you can go customize and take a
look at will keep on adding more and more samples to this as we go and as we find out
...you guys want more scenarios will at them so let's look at...coming back to the movie spots?
Ok, let's shows on the phone to
...so the because this is a universal windows platform app.
It will run seamlessly across phone tablets and
pc's the same the same sample works on the on the phone as well.
It uses the same split view...item if you guys went to the sample
...and there was this between...the same...works ...as
...across cellphone...and pc's.
Now let's look at the movie
...app and the movie spots app we...movie...
Name we came up with it has a basic json file and the json file
as title and actors and directors and more information about the movie
and notice the lat long it also has that...long information about where the movie was shot then I
have a few view model classes create a I create a
parse the json file and I in the movie manager class
...put all of the object I've created into a collection
...collection to display information on the map to
display this information for this app I need a xhtml file and this example
file has all of the other information around the map control then I had
the map controlled this map control I'm customizing to not display other information that
I don't want in app it's not relevant to maps all not show them.
In the core behind file for the map for the main page
...the cs I will go ahead and parse all my collect
cashman collection...to my collection I will
create the new map icons and I will assign that
I properties to them...and I will...them to the location
but I want with but I get from the from my collection and,
I run it and I'll see a bunch of we locations the
...san-francisco on the map these are some pretty icons we
created with if you like them think that...
So, as you can see we have a lot ofmovies...the downtown san francisco and
...displaying that very easily on the map the next thing that I want to do is.
When you click on one of these cameras are the map icons I
want to display some extra information that we had images on file...the title and all
those things so for that I've created a basic users control?
And, in this user control I have a text login list
view and displaying information about the movie as you can see it's the same example that we all know
...about bind it to use data mining and everything I also have a couple of buttons in
their which add the movie location to the to the itinerary and which removes
...location from the identity let's look at the...click event handler?
For the yeah, ad...have adverb,...
so, in the advert click...handler so this is interesting rate I mean I had
geo point and I want I want to display the information for the users instead of
displaying just a lat long they don't really know that lapped law don't real physical address
...don't even know that but I want to show them the real physical address for that I'm using
reverse your coding this is one of the...aps that we have the
mapped location finder service and the map location finder service I...geo point
...get...address...use that formatted address I put in
mike selected itinerary collection that I have a movie manager class and I
build my...identity for the user so now I have my user control already and
it is isset I want to display it
onto the map as remember I how to add the sample to the
map I instantiate the user control in my code behind for the main page.
I attach it to the location which are received from the map element click event and
...to the children collection and I display the map the
...on the map that's run this so as you will see you when you click on one of
these things they will one of these locations you will get a nice-looking
flat-out decent looking...maybe you can do better design java.
So, you have the movie let's add a
and cvs added on the left-hand side I see the formatted address
and displays a formatted address in the list collection of
...so after this point what we did was we did some usability
studies and we saw people cringe...the number of icons are visible on the map
control so we wanted to a cluster
these icons into sort of cluster which will give users a
more cleaner looking view of the map control so, I want
...the hallways I shopped around with my dad lives in the hallways and I talked to people
hey is that it does anyone have a cluster library that I can use I found a
...other friends who had cluster library and that source code is in the cluster library
for I didn't really know how that works but I knew how to call it so
I went ahead and instantiated the cluster library bypassed in
all my movies all the movies that I have I created the cluster every this course is
available for you can download that's a nice clustering library that you can use and,
I also...a converter it needs a converter to know what to look for
...the in the class and how to compare and then I have a
method called refresh map icons so in the refresh map icons I will it
read through the clusters and I will...create the map icons...displayed at
different levels...going through the entire method I'll...look at one of the
codes length so in this one what I have is I look to the cluster
look at the number of elements of...in the cluster and depending on that as select
...image that I want to display?
Then I add the map icon to the collection so this is a
very basic clustering...let's run this and see how that how that looks.
So, this time I'm hoping that...the users will
...bit better.
So, as you can see now this is a little bit more clear and clusters are better
and the displayed the little flashed you're seeing that's known issue it's
...the next flight item if...notice that flash so,
at this point I think I think I have the data displayed onto the map control
...guys want to see that again ok?
So, this is the same universal platform use
...platforms so it'll run nicely on the phone.
And, the clustering libraries for you it's up it's actually a little right now and get help uploaded
...top accountyou can go ahead and downloaded.
So, this one is a little bit responsive I have this...view in
...use my own design I guess and, we also have a nice to
...box...so as you can see this works fine next what I want
is I want to build and itinerary so as I added those things in my selected...
collection I want to display that display of route along the map so what I'll do
is I will iterate through that through all those points that I have in my
selected...and, I will put into the map routes finder service.
...the map...finder service I put in the
points I put in the parameters to optimize on time or distance
...the optimization on time...
So, I'll show I'll allow them to optimize on time and distance then
I will also allow them to put restrictions which was avoid
...highways so on so after this I get a
map router result and the map out result I could easily
...out on the map using the map out view
...in this case I'm going to go through iterate through all those points and I will
display the party-line on map control so I will create a party-line apply
line the line that you can display on the map you provided a geo part and
...display the geo part is part of the results that I'd get out of the map out
finder and I can added to the map elements collection...displays
...polygon then along the...on all the points where the movies are
short...display the camera and this is going to
...display the map element correctly on the map that out clicking on the map
...this mike.
Now after displayed...I'm also resetting the view so that the entire
routers visible as...viewpoints and add them to the...
These are the points where the users really want to go as you can see the have information about the movie in
the text format and now let's look at the show might out.
And, it displays allowed on the map control and,
you can customize this you can customize the map poly lines the color you can customize the
map...thickness so on next what I want to do is.
So, okay, let's revisit what we what we did a
...created some map icon speex added on the map control we
...we added on the map added to the map elements we did some real
...coding we did clustering and finally we did
the map out finder service next what I one is I want
to access uses location and I won the users to come and meet me
...a common point so we can take them on the tour and because it's
a small company I want them to come meet...at a small a good place where I
where my offices so I use the geo located or
of service I request access is think I get the permission once I had
the permission I request the user for the location.
Once I have the location I build a
uri and this is the same you what I service that I was talking about earlier
where you can now launch into the bing maps app built-in windows maps...
And, that will help the that would get the user to where they want.
If the user is, you know, it
is denying are the location access for us then I'm going to display a nice
contin dialogue with a nice message saying hey you seems you did not give
me location access...can go...but if you
want, you know,...you want to ask them to change their mind you can awesome to go to
the privacy settings and change their mind let's run this and see how that how that goes.
Show might get redirects...this is the system prompt that shows up the first-time you do request access
...and I'm going to allow this time.
And, it is going to launch the built-in windows maps app that...shoreline the
keynote today this is build under the same maps platform is available to you.
So, this is the maps app and this is how you the user can get the direction you can just call the
...scheme...directions to it this is...same platform it is very rich
and features as you can see...can search for things you can marketing
...favorite...locations...favorite are you can also explore three-d.
And, that's because of the cities and look at three-d view
of the cities and this is a very rich display of the three-d view.
And, when I saw this the first-time I realize hey, you know,
what I want this in my app and I know mike has worked on it and he's going to help
me out with getting things on the getting three-d view in my map...
So, as ron mentioned for the first-time we are offering aerial three-d and street-side
exploration imagery as part of the windows map platform that you can take advantage of so,
you know, we have this movie spot application and we've seen some really great things with it a
lot of times when you want to do data analysis as a case in point you
want a roadmap as...background because it'll show you all of the location and the
sites and the,... the outline...where the water is but,
it's also very neutral background for your data for showing polygons and poly lines
and map icons but in some other scenarios are you want to take the user
tool location you want them to field in see and...almost get a sense of deja
...of what that location will be like so, for example, if you're building a house
finding application people want to see what's around this potential house
...I'm going to buy what...the neighborhood look like what stores
are nearby so this exploration imagery can be a very key tool
for you to make your application a lot more evocative and will add some to the movies by
application just a second but first let's talk a little bit about this
exploration imagery I mean two things when I say exploration imagery I'm talking about being
aerial three-d and street-side imagery as well that go great together now for being
aerial three-d I'm talking about three sub components of the first for
aerial three-d mode we feature a globe based projection of the world so rather than
having a flat mankato projection which has a lot of conveniences associated with it but has
a downside that extreme latitudes will tend to get a little bit more distorted the globe
...actually show all the area in sort of a more realistic realistically size
...type of format for you it's based on a wg sat for ellipsoid so
it's consistent with your...gps in the gps information you might be getting so
it's a very highly accurate...representation of the world?
Now on top of...production we have digital elevation data that
we've collected from a lot of different sources around the world and then we overlay a lot of
aerial and satellite imagery that we collect ourselves and that we get from a lot of
partners so the result of this is that we have this world the entire world that has
a very high-resolution imagery and you can get very realistic scenes so in
this case you can see behind me there's mounting helen's which erupted in nineteen eighty
and washington and, you know, it was...a very huge mountain...a very
...bigger option and, you can still see from the satellite imagery the reveal
...of where the lava flowed in the dome and...almost
...of this mountain that they explode that's available for-you to ...inside of
your application so if nothing else to your favorite mountain range and take a look at in
the three-d view of the windows and application it should be pretty stunning but the final thing that we
have on top of aerial thirty is three-d cities.
So, you may not know this but microsoft actually has and end-to-end
pipeline for collecting three-d data on cities it starts with the camera
microsoft actually manufactures this camera that's called the ultracam is about the size of
a compact refrigerator it has a number of different lenses in a number of different sensors
in it and we actually fly all over the world and collect information
...so good that we actually sold to other companies as well that use it for
aerial surveying so you know,
if you're in the business of aerial surveying you should definitely consider and...as well but,
we actually take the camera and we put them on planes and when the weather's good...probably it, you know,
summer season will fly-over various cities and
...areas in that city from a lot of different angles and that allows
us to reconstructed and put it back together into a full three-d city so
we've been flying a lot recently and we have over... two hundred
cities in over seventy five thousand square kilometers of three-d space
...flying in north america and europe in australia and asia we've collected a lot of the classic
size of the world so the palaces of madrid or the coliseum in rome or the
...florence we have gold coast in australia so beautiful beaches you can go take
a look at...also collect a lot of cities in north america to so we have chicago in
...york and of course san francisco so check that out...as well but it's not also just
the big cities...collect a lot of smaller and more medium-sized cities so,
for example, sacremento...madison wisconsin or tucson arizona we're
continually gathering more data and making
this available inside of the map application on a month-by-month basis?
So, a lot of you might be familiar with open world video games where, you know,
the open world has maybe twenty or thirty or forty or
fifty square kilometers that you can go walk around then we have seventy five thousand square kilometers
that available to you the developer to feature your application it's almost as big as the size of south
carolina or...every single tree and every single structure and every single
air conditioning unit on top of that...in full
detail with textured with textures on top of it so it's really quite incredible.
So, let's just take a quick look let's go back to that
movie spot application soI love the idea of a movie
...application ... san-francisco has been a very big character and movies I particularly like
the movie bullet so bullet if you're not familiar with it is a nineteen sixty eight car chase
movie starring...queen and it has one of the most iconic car chase
scenes in it and the reason is because it was filmed kind of in downtown san francisco on all around
san francisco so you'll see lots of cars careening around corners
and going over the very steep hills that you see in san francisco so, there's one place, you know,
...in north beach that was one spot where I think is one of some of the famous
...scenes where they're going over hills so, yeah, I guess we can see
with the application that looks pretty good but, you know, what would be even more you know,
evocative if maybe we can see that and aerial three-d let's?
Go port the application over to ariel three-d and,
to do this were essentially just going to add one line of additional zone
...application so in the windows ten map platform we've added a couple of new map
styles aerial three-d.
And,...three-d with roads aerial three-d
will show you the completely natural world devoid of any lines are labels you can see it as if you're
...astronaut from outer space but,
you can also add...three-d with roads and labels and we have a
...extensive labeling algorithm world put on all the various labels for
rosen countries as appropriate ...get included by train and it's really quite
detailed so let's go use...with robles code check this out.
...the application boots...still see san-francisco we're going to be starting with a nader
view top-down on but let's go drill into that location...north...
First will search for the movie bullets we can see just the
bullet sites let's go drill into a goes by and corporate park,
yeah, there you go I think that's the icon create great.
Okay, so, now yes and this I think this is that so you can see that this is a
released detail it's almost like a really gigantic speed bump and you can just imagine cars,
... in a car chase going over this hill and, you know, it almost reminds me of the scene from the
movie so fairly powerful and...sort of manipulated with his fingers and get different
perspectives so you know, aerial three-d really cool for making
and really useful for making various locations very evocative and memorable.
So, yeah,
that's a little bit of a quick view of...adding three-d as you saw was essentially just adding enumeration
...your mapping if we had more time we probably had a couple button so you
can switch between the two.
Okay, well,
the three...very useful but there is an additional complexity you now have to think a little bit more
...three-dimensions.
So, if you've ever develop a map application before you're probably
very familiar with you know-how it works it's a kind of a tile base you very top-down.
go cool all right very top-down it's very straightforward it's based on tiles so,
there's a lot of simple assumptions that you can make when you build your application so, for example,
you're always looking at a rectangle and the top left is this lat long in the bottom right is this lat long
the...slap in the middle so you just divide by two and it's fairly straightforward you know,
there's always a center the center is really the center of gravity so it's pretty straightforward.
When you have to think about three-d things get a little bit more tricky the users looking at a globe in
...probably pivoting down there map...camera to get a good look at
that three-d imagery but when they do that they could be looking off the horizon
so a particular spot that's on the users screen may not actually correspond to a spot
on the map in addition the center of the map is not simply just
...divide by two of the center of the screen again because they're looking at the horizon the
center might be actually much lower and more difficult to compute and the users also not looking
at a strict rectangle they could be looking...oblique perspective that's almost like
...rounded trapezoid in a sense?
So, there's a little bit more complexity there.
In addition you have to think about elevation altitude so the windows
...that platform supports different types of altitude systems that-you might want-to decide to
use ellipsoid is based on sort of
...model of the world that's basically...ellipsoid type of...sphere there's
...which is based on the gravitational model of the world which is a little bit more accurate
and frequently used by gps systems to indicate your altitude but then we also have terrain
...surface so you're going to want to think about what this icon to show up on the train but maybe
under a building or do I wanted to show on top of a building which, you know,
has its own pros and cons...some complexity there but the good news is that we've tried to
make it as easy as possible work with three-d in particular when you're trying to set of
wvu we've added a couple of concepts to hopefully make that easier for you first we've added
the concept of a camera which will give you the perspective that you're looking from so
if you think about a first-person video game this is the sort of
the perspective that you're looking out from and then we have this concept of the scene now seen as a way
for you the developer to provide a description of the thing you want to look at and then
handed over to the windows ten map control and it will try to find the best possible map
view and keep in mind it has to do a little bit more thinking about that it will do the work to
make sure that your view doesn't get obstructed by a mountain or building war, you know, if you
want to look at something in denver and denver's, you know, five or six thousand feet up that will put
...the right position to see that in addition it's very important to have very
smooth animations and transitions as users go from point-to-point and these sets
seen api is a map dot prices
...will also come up with the right a animation to easily and naturally
transducer transition the user from one point to the next so this is the call map
...seen a saying it's very similar to the tricycle
...saying and what it takes...a map...object and we have a lot of constructors for building that?
So, let's just take a quick look at making the map a little bit more evocative by using these new api
is so as rohan added earlier we have a clustering api so that
we show where there's a lot of potential movie locations and
...three-d mode what I want to do now is when somebody clicks on a cluster I
...make sure that ...make sure that we show a really great three-d perspective that users know that they can sort of,
you know, drag-and-drop and move around so we've commented out...tricycle...a
...call and replaced it with tries that...
Now in particular we have a method called map seen dot create from location radius...
pass in the location that were using before ...addition it has a radius property of
the radius is sort of a different alternative
zoom level in some ways a better alternative zoom level what it says is here's show me
this center point but then show me this many meters around this center point so,
for example, if you think about the standard city block being
hundred-meters why'd passing a value of five hundred basically says show me about
ten city blocks around this particular radius so it's a lot easier to reason about,
you know, do you want to show ten city blocks, you know, five hundred-meters or you want to show the entire city,
you know,
san francisco I think is seven kilometers wide so something a little bit bigger might be more useful if you want to the
...show someone the entire view of san francisco the other thing we want to pass in is a
...to look at so forty five degrees means...but let's look at
and easily directions let's change that...and the final parameters pitch
...pitches how decline the camera will be fifty is somewhat the climate's go a little
bit further and sixty-degree angle so that we get a really good perspective we'll try that out so,
now...still start off with a top-down view of
san-francisco to start with you can see the entire area but when you click
on a cluster we'll get a beautiful view of it and see that it did in animation to take me
to that location and now I can see downtown san francisco which is where all these movie scenes
are you can see things like the trans america...made you can see,
you know, the...center where or at you can see
markets tree cutting through those you can see all the map icons
and map icons are appropriately included based on whether they're sort of behind buildings
...fated if it's if it's close by so,
setting a oblique perspective like this actually helps bring users into the map
and makes it a little bit more evocative?
All right so aerial three is the way to sort of see things from
...to see things as if you had a magic helicopter and could file of the world
street-side is the compliment to that this actually lets you see things from the human
...ground-level...so street-side
...a is a huge effort we have you know, we're building our own streetside imagery may have seen a
being street-side...by your neighborhood perhaps we're expanding our
...coverage for the bing street-side feature every for meters those cars drive
they take fifty-five megapixels worth of imagery and, we collect all of that and great
...is that we now make that available to the developer to use as a control in your map
application so this is a great...to the aerial three-d can put the two together and really see
some really nice imagery you can see here this is the top of the
...streets at lombard street you can see our
...labeling algorithm is struggling to keep up with the angle of roads there of course you can
see very beautiful perspective of san francisco and...tower in the background as well?
So, using street-side is actually fairly simple it's essentially just two lines of code.
Now we are expanding our coverage for street-side quite a bit but we don't cover
everywhere yet so the first one of code that you're going to want to write is essentially a check in with a
check will say is...latitude and longitude is there a
streetside panorama near me a bubble if you will that I can look around
...for that given location now here in san francisco because there's a lot
of coverage there's always streetside panoramas nearby again...you know,
driving every for meters were collecting essentially bubbles worth of data.
Now if I successfully get back a streetside panorama then
I can do is I can create what's called a street-side experience so the
street-side is essentially a mode of the map control the
user interface works a little bit differently you can only jump from bubble you can look around the bubble but,
it doesn't work quite the same ways the map does so it's what we call a street-side experience so return on
street-side experience I just set map dot custom experience to that new streetside
experience with the panorama and then some additional parameters to say what my initial heading
...pitch should be inside of the bubble so two lines of code and a way you go.
So, let's go extend the movie spots application to incorporate
this streetside experience so as I mentioned it's essentially just a
...the map control so we're going to add a map control towards
...which will hold the street-side experience so we've got another map control there this is
...be inside of our movie info panel that we added earlier and now I just need a
...the streetside panorama so when the info panel get shown we're going to consider whether to show
street-side as well.
As I mentioned the first couple lines of code will just say hey is
there streetside panorama near this location here almost surely there will be but in
the case there isn't one let's just go hide the street-side map control and get on with our lives but, when there is
one we're going to instantiate that street-side experience now we have a couple of different variables that you can use
to customize the streetside experience to turn off, you know,
some of the buttons zoom buttons so that you get a very pure view if you will of the
streetside location then finally words...that custom experience on the map control?
So, let's take a look at this let's go back to our bullet location so I think that is the spot movie
where the car chases were but, let's take a look at, you know, the...I view if you will of that place.
Go back to the north beach area organism in a little bit further
out there you go.
Yet see the beautiful speed bump that's...essentially and now when
we click on it you can see that the info panel came up and now we can actually see the
streetside experience hosted inside that info panel so you can see...almost like a little bit of
us ski jump in a...it's very steep and you can imagine how, you know,
a car chase would be kind of exciting going over that city over that particular scene so
of course reliance able to manipulated and able to look around and go to different bubbles you know, again,
there's, there's options in your user interface affords is that we can show as well if we wanted to but
use wanted to show the...view here as well so...really interesting I want, you know,
encourage you to think about street-side not just as a compliment to
...but think about it is its own standalone control so, for example,
if you've got a customer relationship database and you have to show, you know,
thousands of potential customers...street-side control on your customer
form and that would give your sales people perspective of here's this customer here's
...headquarters is here's what it looks like you can easily add a lot of very interesting detail and
...any application that deals with location it uses the map
controls its foundation but it doesn't have to necessarily go along with the map control so
think about different scenarios where this might be useful for you...look forward to seeing what you can build with that.
Okay, so,
we've taken the movie spot application we've...as they can see all the movie spots and
san-francisco we've added aerial three and street-side so you basically
...away from this you know, all the tools I think you need to build...really great map application I think all
the code we showed except the clustering stuff basically show you all the code the movies
by application so you've got that your tool belt how about some tips and tricks?
Hello, yeah, so, I think.
Beaver able to see the map control we added map icons we added
...be customize the canvas we displayed in three-d and we displayed across
...and pc's the there is a few couple of tips and tricks...that I want to remind you
guys before we move away from your of july schemes again this is very important
and very powerful tool make sure you explore that before you start writing
...custom experiences try to get back on what's already there then map
elements,... this two different ways to display things on the map
...map elements are things that you can embed inside of the map control and the map
seen as you saw those map icons when they were behind the buildings there was
...slight occlusion how they were part of the scene whereas when there was
example on the screen it was on top of the building so
be sure on what your experience wants and what you want to take a
...app we recommend using map elements for a large number of collection that you want to display on the
map and...example for other additional information as you saw in our app then
...location make sure you use write checks make sure you ask
...permission when you're calling geo location from the background thread make sure you come back to the
...thread before you ask for user before you oscar
...location
...we have a couple of api we've done three-d in street-side support
on a variety of devices almost all devices have three-d and street-side support
but because of hardware resource constrains some devices might not have pd
and...support so we have provided reduce with you with some of the
helpfully api so you can query...that is free...on...devices are not
...just a few tips and tricks maybe you have more questions we can talk about it in the insiders launch?
as you saw along the way we have...like a bunch of features that room...because of what
...deceived and we would like to continue to work on that and you have we
have the user ways link ...of the feedback specific ones that...are
...is offline map support on desktop and
...actually run the features that you guys requested a...in the previous release in
windows forty-point one performance offers...the map control was another big feedback that
...and we continue to invest in that...map icon visibility the collision
behavior desired property was also result of a direct feedback from you z next
networks find with the map icahn dot collusion behavior desired property so
the index across of different map icons works as you would expect and it is good
...a few new events map element click
...for the map elements so these are these are things that
...direct result of your feedback we have a help customization of the canvas
can display businesses on the canvas and you can hide them finally have a cup
a few custom controls on top of the map control these are the ones which you would
expect forfrom for zoomfor zoom
built rotate for mouse of ordinances and these are coming in the future
...so these are these as basic feedbacks a few take
...that if I have to recommend something for you to do after this right after this would be make sure you
will explore the built-in default windows maps app
this is built on top of the same maps platform that is
available to you see what the maps app is capable of doing and...use if you have questions
...insiders launch about how we using the maps platform in the maps app kick-start
challenge after you've seen this...we've, you know, taken you through the basics of the map control
quoting the quick such allen's on your points it should be very easy for you
...those...familiarize yourself with the maps platform
...a couple of sessions that I want you guys to make...order of there's one on friday ...by
...burnett he's going to talk about the web control the bing
maps web control and this is for your cross-platform applications on the web.
Then we have ...of...can-we doesn't insiders launch and if you have any questions
we are verify the ninety minutes and will be helping out view you should
build beautiful apps using the maps platform and is available ready for you to do right now as you
...app and all the source...available we have the resources up
right now you can go check it out is already they don't get hub we also have a sample from last
...built talk which was a windows phone eight-point one sample we...created that
...was a very easy task...that windows stand and that's source code is available as is
...lot of ui...but it's there as is and it's also available out there
...good bunch of msdn sources and documents for-you the launch of what I
samples there and that's a...any questions?
So, is it possible to build...by then opt offline map
...integration so turn by turn directions are not currently supported in the public
dpi surface one-button as...like you mean a developing service from a to be yes that is
...services map mapped out finder service should be available to you in the
offline maps but to get the full turn by turn directions experience we don't have control for the
full turn by turn experience for that you want to use of the uri activation that rancho
did launch the windows and map app and that will do turn by turn directions offline as well?
So, the question is there a javascript api for all of this as well so
...we'll talk a lot about our javascript api is on friday we have the...the ajax
...control that has a lot of these services, for example, routing and driving directions we don't
have three and street-side yet we definitely know there's a lot of interest in that and,
you know,...be good to hear your scenarios as well so, we don't have a yet but,
we have the ajax have a control which is very flexible used...of solutions and...we'll talk about that on friday.
So, the question is, you know, what's the costing and what's the charge for that so.
We've as ron mentioned we actually have unifier token services that being map spoils you go to
the...common get one when you get...basically a basic token and,
that supports free usage for a comparatively high a number of...
Fifty thousand transactions a day for a windows application specifically so,
it's two thousand transactions a day if you need to go more than that then we have a
sales team that can sort of, you know, reach out and work and see if you need to go above.
But, the first fifty thousand are per day or free and that really was...probably solve, you know,
the ninetieth percentile applications that we thinkor out there.
So, the question is for data for
cities what's our what's our road map and what's our plan so.
Some of you may be familiar with...imagery that was a part of the windows
...we had the three-d map preview application where this was initially featured
in launch statically at something like forty cities in about a year-and-a-half we've gone to
two hundred cities we've also been able to fly bigger cities because we've actually improved are
camera hardware to make sure that we can get great views of urban canyons so,
that's when the beauties of owning the pipeline so we've got from about forty two hundred I would
...might expect something similar to that as we go over time,
you know,...sometimes limited by, you know, we can't really...winter months and we have a lots of lags
...rand-r collection but that's the kind of the rate that we've been growing and that's
what we expect to grow for...three-d imagery for street-side as I mentioned
were already rapidly sort of expanding how we cover that so that's grown quite a bit and covered as well.
Can you actually get...offline now?
So, there is a system-wide setting
probably the user and the user selects the map that they want to select they want to download
...a system...white setting group to get data we can should you and, once the
...is unloaded by the user it's not something that you can do as a developer all you can do is you can
call-in...can do you can call into the offline map display screen in the system,
system you why and, the user has to download the download the map themselves.
So, when the user...the question is that a single transaction when the user when
the user goes the system-wide...on the side...download a new map that's,
you know, independent of your application and,
when you use some of the map data we won't necessarily you know, charger transaction for that and if you
use...around it you would but for using offline data that should not...transaction so,
yeah, now that you're downloading california that's available on behalf of
all applications plus the out-of-the-box map application because it is built on...platform so,
yeah, so, it's available system-wide?
Question moi.
The question is...going to be more restriction
...information about highways in terms of the height of the trucks so
on that's good feedback we'll look into that.
Yeah,we continually work with a lot of our map data providers to improve the state of
our map data and that's definitely one of the areas that...would
...get better fidelity on that will work with our various map providers to get...it is,
you know, there's a lot of different providers in the world and lifetimes the data quality can be
different in the product offerings are different so we always try to source as I like to say artisans
...hands lacked all the data that we're going to...available to make I wanted...to
...hills while I'm walking so I mean we are working through all...and...the user...site
...we're like people to go and...on these are features.
Question moi.
So, the question is for the...offerings is altitude available
...given lat long position it's not available directly through an api that's
...the control we do have a being web service that does
get you can use to get the altitude for location but, ...yeah,
like I said it's not going strictly through our three-d imagery that's going through a web service to get the
altitude forgiven location but if you do set...to be...yeah,
we, yeah, so, for example, if you set the altitude, you know, hundred surface
then, you know, whether you're on top of the golden gate bridge or whether you're sort of in the middle...desert will always put
you hundred-meters above that particular location but getting the
...underneath your a given lat...you have to have a web service for that.
Question.
Repeat the question so the question is can we use the map...fashions
...data mining for...right now we have support for map items control for those animals
...children and we're looking into bringing support for that...the map elements as well
so, in the past we have done...support for the map control if...working towards
a map elements of in the currents...is a bug for the map elements not working on
...to that but sample to reach work correctly for the map items control.
So, the question is there a way to import your own
three-mile unfortunately there is in a way there is not a way to
importer three-d model but it's a great feedback that we're taking should talk to
get more about corrugated more about the scenarios so looks like we should probably
...be in the ask the experts section over on the other side of
the second-floor and will be happy to take your questions more the outsiders launch...tires
...don't forget to evaluated helps us to brewer...thank you?